hello we'll wait for a little bit for a
few people to come in here you guys know
I love freedom but you know as they say
freedom is under attack freedom isn't
free you know all those general-purpose
slogans about freedom so we're gonna
have a little conversation about freedom
and we're gonna announce our little
discount and yeah that's what we're
gonna do today
yeah let's give it at least this way for
at least 20 I'm wearing a freedom shirt
right now what do y'all think I'm
keeping this freedom shirt so actually
we're gonna make it 18 freedom shirts
for freedom not 19 it was originally 19
but I'm wearing this one I'm not gonna
give you the one I wore I wouldn't do
that
Yeah right this is the most limited
edition comma merch ever to drop oh can
we make them tighter yeah so that's kind
of the problem yeah of course I work out
bro gotta work out you got to be jacked
yeah yeah freedom shirts right no no if
you purchased it a week ago you can't
get the shirt all right you got to buy a
new one and no tolerance on this if you
try to like do some crap like I'm gonna
return it or I'm gonna cancel my order
you'll get a freedom shirt because
freedom isn't free are they legal in
communist countries I don't think we
shipped to Venezuela I don't think so I
don't think so
are they legal and uh yeah you know okay
let's talk about freedom okay so a few
things we made some changes to this cord
freedom does not mean anarchy freedom
does not mean that everybody can do
whatever they want whenever they want
this leads to a terrible society this
leads to a terrible community so we're
uh you know we're gonna we're gonna
crack down a bit on the discord
um you know just against general like
shitposting derailment low-quality
comments if it's a high quality
community we're gonna make it that way
no Anarchy doesn't mean freedom at all
anarchy just means that the tyranny you
don't get to choose who enforces the
tyranny anarchy just means that any any
you know Joe Schmo with a gun can can
can be your your Lord so yeah I mean you
know this is important it's an important
time to have discussions like this about
freedom if you guys don't know I really
love freedom I really do I really do you
know okay so the other thing we're gonna
talk about is I know the last stream we
talked about hiring and we get a lot of
emails from people who are like hey bro
I know I'm not qualified but I'm willing
to work for free you're not working for
free you're asking us to educate you for
free if you genuinely wanted to work for
free and some people do and we love
these people
they're sending pull requests on our
github to open pilot you can work for
free all you want right but if you're
asking to come to this office and you
want to work for free what you're doing
is you're lowering the bar in the office
right that you'd be doing I like every
person we hire here I really want them
to bring up the bar which means that
every person every new person we hire
has to be better than the current
average at comma and that's how you get
a a community a country a world that's
continually improving because if you're
hiring people who are worse than the
average
your your your community your company or
whatever is declining and you know I
don't know anything about Amazon
leadership principles um but yeah so
we're cracking down against you know
general junk in the discord - it's a
high quality developer community um
that's what our products are - right our
products are all development gifts if
you come in with the mentality that your
consumer
you join the comic community intending
to extract value to extract more value
than you give back the problem with that
is um well you know if everybody comes
in with that mentality it's not a very
nice community it's not one you want to
be in either there's that really great
post about about subcultures and how to
make sure they don't to climb so yeah
hopefully everybody understands you know
you just got in a big conversation being
had now about content moderation on the
internet yeah you you empathize a whole
lot more the people have to make the
decisions so I mean what the comic
community I hope there is there's
there's no questions it's not a
community for general socialization it's
not a community for shit-talking it's
community for discussion about comic
products and comma software and
improving them and kind of your status
in that community and we're gonna make
this more explicit is have you submitted
pull requests have you submitted code
have you improved other people's lives
in that community and you're giving back
you know give back to the community
right or you know get that get the boot
just purchasing a product purchasing a
product entitles you to that piece of
hardware it doesn't um and we're gonna
make this clear as well look if our
hardware is broken like the hardware is
broken like we shipped you something
that's broken
this is absolutely our problem uh and we
want to fix that if the problem is that
you can't figure out how to use the
product that's a problem with you and
this is why we have the the 30-day
money-back guarantee okay uh now that
stuff's out of the way of course I hire
people smarter than love to hire people
smarter than you got to bring the bar up
and my the smartest guy comma hell no no
no I think I think better marketing is
in a way exactly the problem right one
of when my co-workers brought up at
lunch today that if you're Wendy's are
in and out right the only things you're
competing on basically our customer
support you're not competing on burgers
we're competing on a technical product
we're competing based on the quality of
our level two driving system and
compared to other people's right another
thing that I think a lot of people don't
get about , is this is the company
mission solve self-driving cars while
delivering shippable intermediaries
right it's not to continually make more
money we need to make enough money in
order to accomplish that goal but money
doesn't necessarily know having more
money doesn't necessarily help you with
that goal it maybe can hurt you I'm so
our goal is to keep you know profits
basically to the point where we're
covering expenses which we have for the
whole year are going beyond that we
don't care we're not trying to expand
this community to everybody if you don't
have what it takes to you know not even
what it takes you know what I shouldn't
say that because it's not really a skill
based thing it's a mentality based thing
if you come into the it doesn't matter
what skill you have maybe self-awareness
you need self-awareness but other than
that it's not like you have to be like
some you know ten years of experience
program or anything like that this is
for joining the community not for coming
to work here
um but you have to have an expectation
that you're not good you're not there to
consume product ban from reddit you're
there to join a community where you're a
fellow developer right you're buying a
development kit if you're just here to
to take I want an experience I want an
experience there's a hundred thousand
other companies that are out there
begging to cater to you and all they
want from you is their money we're not
one of those so you know that's what it
is that said I'm gonna change we're
gonna change it now that to only uh
to only that's that we don't want your
money it's not that we don't want your
money and we certainly appreciate our
consumers are our customers but not if
you know they're there to demand more
than what they purchased right okay so
we're gonna limit the number of times
this can be used we're gonna change it
to eighteen the discount code goes live
tomorrow on July 4th
and the discount code is freedom shirt
so you will get a free freedom shirt
with your comma to purchase if you
purchase it tomorrow
freedom shirt I will show you some of
the freedom shirts you can put in the
description make sure to get your order
in as close to midnight as possible
these are the sizes that we have of the
freedom shirts you can see we have many
freedom shirts in this freedom shirt
bucket there's a lot of freedom in here
so much freedom so much freedom so much
freedom so much freedom so much for you
you're in the freedom shirt box um now
you asked George why aren't you doing a
discount on comma twos I'm wearing a
medium right now this is a medium no I
so yeah they run a little bit small you
can really see my chest so we're not
discounting we're not just counting
comet twos period but we've never done
it discount in the comet two and I'll
tell you the truth why this is the comma
to production facility this the bins
marked past are all the comma twos that
we have so we have about 58 comma twos
and then we have these ones up here
testing to the green ones past red ones
failed notice why these ones failed CPU
temperature too hot so we fixed a lot of
the heat issues by screening out well
this has been true for a while so yeah
that's why that's why there's no
discount on the comma to is when there
was eons we had many many eons in stock
you know we had we had boxes and boxes
of eons and of course I wanted to you
know move that product right now if you
guys are under 100 comma tools tomorrow
yeah but I'm wearing the freedom sure
you want to say hi to the the youtubers
yeah I'm sliding
yeah yeah check out the freedom shirt
man I think I look good in the freedom
shirt
yeah this 18 freedom shirt cuz this is
19 I stole the freedom shirt to women's
largest sevens mas oh it's a woman's
lawyer medium weight the women's largely
smaller the same size I'm wearing a
medium yeah this is a compression shirts
for working out yeah it's for working
out it makes you muscles look big when
you look in the mirror like that yeah
you know Sam I like the arm kama yeah
arm coming this is this is the most
exclusive merch honestly you guys
there's 18 of these in the world so you
better get your order in at midnight
tonight that's midnight PDT I'll show
you what I set it to in Shopify and I
swear I'm not gonna to change it so I
don't know what time this actually is in
your time zone bye
yeah yeah I think we're gonna limit it
to one use per customer you know one
freedom shirt per customer
you don't need more freedom shirts than
one don't be greedy with the freedom
there's plenty of freedom for everybody
what Nozomi there's only eight it is a
limited supply that's true you're gonna
flip it on eBay for profit yeah so it
only comes with a comma to you use the
code freedom shirt a check out tomorrow
starting at and I already said if
anyone's like oh I want to return it
till I can get a freedom shirt now
well you can buy it tomorrow but if you
cancel an order and then you try to add
freedom shirt later you don't get afraid
of shirt if you're trying to pull some
no freedom shirts for you I was
talking a little bit about discoid yeah
I did talk to them about working for
free and I talked to them how actually
it's kind of disrespectful because what
you're actually doing is you're asking
us to educate you for free and if you
want me to educate you hook up with
Harvard charges I've charged double
[Laughter]
it's twice the education it's twice the
education exactly for twice the price
that's right so that's what if you want
to come to kama and be educated you pay
us 100k yes if you just go out there and
find our programming challenge you're
great you know what else
if you submit if you contribute dean lee
special shout out to Dean Lee doesn't
join the discord just submit pull
requests on github see that's the kind
of contribution we like you want to work
for us for free do that don't send an
email saying you want to work just go
work bro yeah you're asking me to manage
you for free is that what you're asking
permission how people want permission
how their life works I mean I don't know
how to live work you're gonna be in the
frame you got to be in the frame here
you know take a chair welcome to the
chats touch chats with the executive
team Akane I yeah yeah we're gonna talk
to y'all about culture today our lunch
chat today was how much the discord
sucks and how we're gonna remove a lot
of the low-quality from it I think
you understand where we are in our cycle
as our as a company I don't know
anything about cycles we're not a
corporation that's right we're never
gonna be a corporation that's right the
customer can be wrong I mean look we
like her cos they're wrong they're just
not right I mean you know what yeah
actually that's not true whether the
customer is wrong or right we judge you
by nature standards whatever nature
standards are right have we considered
becoming a non-profit no nonprofit
company so in a way we're really not
that dissimilar from every other tech
startup out there right a lot of tech
startups brag about being pre-revenue
honestly I'd rather get money from
committed users who want to help develop
who want to join look do you say it all
the time we're incredibly open I love
being open with you guys I'm more open
with you than I am with VCS I think a
lot of Biscay to see source coming here
than a lot of you
um but the flipside of that is where
technically I mean in a lot of ways
we're pre-revenue startup commas
multi-billion dollar exit doesn't come
from us selling a comma to to you it's a
laughable amount of money it comes from
us solving self-driving cars which is
our mission right yeah we're just trying
to solve self-driving cars we're not
trying to yeah build a massive
corporation we're not trying to build a
consumer I mean we sell these products
as dev kids basically just so people who
want to come develop with our stuff have
an easy way to enter the ecosystem you
know you don't have to pay us a dollar
you can figure out how to build all of
Comus stuff all the stuff you need is
post it online for free if you know how
to find it right now it's a big part of
it no comma - is not free but you can go
you can build a neo board which for the
most part still works you can buy the
cheapest phone off ebay you can 3d print
your own case right if you want to join
this this this ecosystem you can join it
for nothing but if you want it to be
easy and nice so if I covet ooh right
now if you want support easy and nice
that's a lot easier sure for the most
part if you buy if you buy a comma - and
you don't have any unrealistic
expectations like a torque mod for your
Honda you can have a good time I think
it is not managing expectations and
we're working on doing that a little bit
better the bar used to be a lot higher
it's moved a little bit and we're gonna
continue to try to talk more about what
is what a good community member looks
like a whole lot of uh look if you um
purchase a comma - and you never send us
the support request and you figure out
how to do everything you're good we like
you alright if you expect support if you
expect to be treated a certain way you
shouldn't buy the product from us right
yeah I think it's pretty clear but the
flipside of that
and like why I feel ok saying all this
is because well if you have a problem
with all the pilot you don't have to
rely on us you can rely on yourself
no it's open source right and that's the
beauty of open source it's very unfair
for company says there's no support and
if it doesn't work get bucked all right
we don't say that we say there's no
support if it doesn't work you have
access to most of the same stuff we have
access to almost everything this is also
why we have a one-year warranty on the
hardware the hardware is not open source
but we warranty yet we make sure it'll
market there's any actual defects in the
hardware we will fix them we'll really
try to do a great job with that if
there's a problem with the software or
if there's a problem with you figuring
out how to use the software it's open
source bro
you shut them all the testing they're
doing yeah yeah you want to get yourself
some testing if I call comi I support
there is no comment I support somebody
asks for a phone number and we laughed
at them I mean there's an email there's
an email support a comment i but most of
what's the point of comma a I will tell
you is if it's a hardware defect we'll
look into it
otherwise fix this offer yourself we
have a 30 day money-back guarantee yeah
I think that's pretty clear
oh really I'm much more to say about
that yeah oh yeah no we've been working
really hard luck no there's some talk
about well why don't you like gated why
don't you make people like do a
programming test for them to be able to
buy stuff like we don't want to add
artificial difficulty to this right very
talented
you know programmers are people who are
on the community or are busy they
shouldn't have to it shouldn't mean that
they shouldn't have a good experience we
want to make the experience as good as
possible right but think of the
experience more like maybe the hard part
of the experience not the soft part of
the experience mistakes maybe we should
change our email to the hardware support
a comment oh it's not a bad idea yeah
yeah I think that does make it a little
bit more clear yeah because to be only
said yeah cuz we only sell hardware yeah
yeah yeah
there's lots of people on discord who
were very helpful and I would I don't
know how much you've said but we're
really grateful to our moderators and
people who have to help everybody in
discord there's a lot yeah yeah there's
a lot of great people great content in
the discord we really you know by
getting rid of all the less good stuff
we really did Stu let them shine more
than anything else yeah yeah uh yeah
order support
yeah but order like people think they're
entitled to support for open pilot
they're not I do see what do you think
that
because you know they didn't really like
look into what it was they just like you
know try they cause some software they
just followed some tutorial they read
online not put out by us and then in
that case think I asked them for support
right oh yeah if you ordered a Bosch
harness and you received an ID act
absolutely we had to read three people
this week I heard there was an amount we
shouldn't even we didn't make up set it
back but you said it free we sent a new
ones what seven free new ones yes right
when we deal with that right what
percent of the emails are crap um we do
ignore stupid emails I mean we do our
best to ignore thing but there's a lot
of inbound we're very small team so
continuing trying to just stop the top
of the funnel for being so big yeah make
a helpline for the software they didn't
you about the Nintendo Power out line
back in the day should we charge two
dollars a minute
just imagine you purchased Super Mario 3
and you couldn't get past the third
level in the fourth world do you think
you can call Nintendo and ask for
support we're just not there yet
we're never gonna be there we saw that
kids today we felt that kids are we
gonna stop that guy I think it's clear
what you get dev stands for developer in
case anyone's confused about yeah duh
dev watts of sport if you're not a
developer we don't recommend you buy
this product that's right but remember
that being said like I really don't want
to exclude people because they think
that like I don't know how to program
right you don't have to know how to
program things just be patient you
having to learn willing to learn that's
it I know we asked sailfin
self-aware self-aware your
self-awareness yeah yeah snaps for
self-awareness uh software support with
Prime subscription and why does
everybody what support does everybody
need so they don't want support you see
they they get it and then like they're
Hana doesn't have enough torque so they
want the Torquemada alright which is
super dangerous by the way
safety is very
she's very important um that's one of
our main issues in the desert or you
know there there's lots of like yeah
cool you take them back there yeah yeah
we took him back there briefly are there
secrets
I get nervous taking chunk people around
back there - from where out a little bit
more and then we'll do one more pull for
the free shirt categories for aired wait
a pole what you say polar pole a pole
just a show
uh-huh no the pole Church wants people
to work for free whoa no I well people
email us and say hey I know I'm not
qualified for this job but I'm willing
to work for free and like you understand
that that costs us as a company more
than we gain I mean oh comma pencil yeah
people you know we weren't talking about
how comma pencil is one of the nicest
channels on discord it's really nice
people are contributing doing the great
work you know we're sending out Eric B
and PJ la are gonna get free comma twos
when we uh I mean I think they've been
the biggest two contributors maybe some
of the other people who can contributing
and give like a hundred bucks off or
something we are gonna do um maybe some
new merch let's yeah yeah listen the
fillings act people here's you know
here's your kind of like here's you
where you start out right every time you
contribute something you go up every
time you know you say something stupid
oh yeah ask for support you go down
karma I knew there's no expectations are
are challenging yeah
don't have expectations don't have
expectations that's right under promise
over performance we are here to under
promise the out of all evil that's
right you won't get anything they'll
send us money and we won't send you
anything that's a lot we really try to
come up every Monday and Tuesday you
guys something is gonna happen with the
common points or something I think we
can tell them the word it doesn't mean
anything
Epcot grows you heard of Epcot get ready
for the up hide turn are you leaking
it's not leaking it's just a pot it
doesn't mean anything
I mean they can do Google does Epcot
mean something if you google it know
what they know where it's derived from
yeah they'll never figure it out man
they'll never figure it out
it's a comer is it a rash guard what
nuts is this a your birds are for him
you know it's just like papi who knows
man well this was an ambitious former
comma employee project it'll push ups
grows if it's built all right my
battery's dying wait I love this on the
label did you show them what they're
showing the label it says made in the
USA freedom I can't read it's backwards
it says seven days no training makes one
week that's right that's how we calm a
phone you know performance fabric all
right I'm gonna show in the back a
little and then yeah chill for how you
can get a freedom shirt you're not on a
gimbal you're sitting on the table sorry
do we even have a good book yeah we had
one Mona where it is can I buy a comment
to a doge coin I mean you can convert
your doge coin to cash and then by a
comma - that's right pet name for common
customers is calm I don't think we've
ever come on come on come on discuss
scope is done but a periscope died
George you were out to scam us
we want comic of oh the coveralls were
the best you feel scary good maybe we'll
do a special edition cover all um
they're expensive though can you use a
common tail with a board I don't know
man
a comet - is just hardware we sell you
hardware can you use it with a
television maybe I don't know , boxers
George couldn't hack aboard
our commenters are like it's like
discord in here no they're pretty bad
can I use common Russia you can use it
anywhere there's roads I think the
freedom sure it's free all right guys
I'm gonna put my mask on when you buy a
comma - wait why are you putting a mask
on you know it's important to be safe
from coronavirus I'm worried about some
of those people in discord giving me
kind of ours
I'm within six feet of them you know all
right we're going all right we're going
you want a sweat flip the camera on you
can you can hold the camera no you're
better at it than me it's unclear well I
don't know yeah the secrets I'll show
you could show them this guy's the dance
the data center is growing yeah the
models are getting huge yeah just this
oh this is good George is using a mask
because we're toxic production we just
we just reorganized all the shelving uh
really ramping up production but comment
who's irate where they're selling so
fast oh thanks guys
this is how we manage and measure our
yields every week here's our past band
and yeah yeah that's really long
these are from our 3d printers also
we're looking for Moore's or tracked
m200 no we're not moving production to
China anytime soon we produce
can we meet production guy guys can see
the team beautiful flash and uno boards
oh man do they know we do a really
thorough testing yeah got to get that
success one off here damn look at the
back guys can see virtually Chris back
here also if you're interested we got
sweet acts of UPS's I don't wanna buy
these Oh
oh my god shirts we're giving them away
tomorrow only tomorrow this is the most
exclusive car mentioned in history
wow you own something Wow yeah I'm
keeping this one we have 18 more they're
gonna be given away to the first 18
people who buy tomorrow with code
freedom sheriff tomorrow's at midnight
starting
yeah PDK don't mess it up those are
great shirts
chase oh hi so alright know what should
we let unlimited people use the code
freedom sure and then only the first day
team will get it how is that that much
different from just giving a clean out I
think we have a good system going
there's only 18 for you insurance then
there was a only up rate a mess we can
get people to buy
what if whoa we know I got an idea okay
no new play no seriously play better
rated to get money we're gonna you as
many people as want to use freedom sure
tomorrow if you use the code freedom
shirt you enter into the freedom shirt
lottery every time a to you by enters
you once into the freedom shirt lottery
okay yeah and then we're gonna do dice
to determine which order numbers get
free of insurance Oh that'll be great
stream oh I love it
oh well not stream there's no more usage
limits on freedom sharing every comment
to you purchase don't show them this to
make sure people know you know when it
is what it's scheduled it's not illegal
it's a look it's a loot box actually go
um no you can have it you could have a
lottery I believe the lotteries allowed
is really can I show the Hyundai Sonata
it's illegal banned for life we could
use some more high-profile officers if
we could George doesn't have that enough
high-profile lawsuits in its life um
loot box is not a lottery that's correct
[Music]
we request it yeah they are very rare
yeah
I entertain requests time I said uncle
your local Hyundai dealership
these are ultra radar creatures they
look so soft
no pretty nice yeah I'm gonna put one on
later all right
tomorrow we did it to PDG every tomorrow
everyone gets a free t-shirt if we get
less than 18 everyone gets a freedom
shirt we get more than 18 lottery sorry
leaf box whatever the most legal way to
stay that says you're looking fit raffle
thanks alright alright I think that's it
alright yeah discord we're really trying
to make everything higher brow higher
brown community if you're here to be a
leech don't fire Chelsea have you
listened to anything we've said today if
we buy a common tool you show me the
Hyundai Sonata
Barnaby says sure can they listen to
anything we've said today how many more
times do we need to say it yeah yeah
encourage things like that you know back
when we needed money
watch all right we calling it yeah I
think we called it yeah oh my god my
house is a car manufacturers lock the
comma to zap answer this question all
the time why why do people think it's
gonna happen well we can't yeah they are
aware that Apple and Sony couldn't keep
me out right like software companies do
they think that like Honda and Toyota
can keep me out bro what did I say last
time that was asked dog means never
having to say you're sorry I think we
under it create a wiki for FAQ I think
we did all right bye-bye